这是二零二三年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分第一次考试。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意。
回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
And I thought I'd phone to find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
Er, what kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers, and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day, except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
OK. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form and
some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
the test. after three A, B, and
听力考试正式。
开始，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答。
有关小题和阅读下一小题，
Read Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷。
上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Billy needs some beans for his science project at school.
Maybe we can stop by a store on our way home.
Let's go to Green's.
It's just around the corner.
Okay. Hi, Stephen.
Guess who I saw at the city library?
Andy Clarks, the leading actor in The Good Lawyer, the famous TV series.
What was he doing there?
His popularity has slipped since the final season of the show.
It seems as if everybody's talking about Jason's retirement.
Yes. His office is filled with gifts.
I gave him a T -shirt with a baseball pattern on it.
That's nice. I'll get him something this afternoon.
Hope it's not late.
Did you go to Cooper's last night?
No. Was there anything special?
Yes. The employees dressed up as movie characters, and every customer received a
discount card. That was interesting.
Oh, the road is jammed with traffic again.
We're going to be late for work.
Let's make a U -turn at the next crossroads and try another way.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个。
小题：从题中所给的
three A, B, and lasts
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间
阅读各个小题，每小题
五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七。
两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Do you think Janet could make it?
I'm sure she can.
Have you tried calling her?
Yes, of course.
But I can't get through.
The flight has already been called twice.
What are we going to do?
Bored without her?
I should have reminded her at the office yesterday.
She may have totally forgotten it.
Take it easy, Sarah.
Let me call her home number.
Oh, there she is.
Do you think Janet could make it?
I'm sure she can.
Have you tried calling her?
Yes, of course.
But I can't get through.
The flight has already been called twice.
What are we going to do?
Bored without her?
I should have reminded her at the office yesterday.
She may have totally forgotten it.
Take it easy, Sarah.
Let me call her home number.
Oh, there she is.
Let call Welcome to our program, Miss Johnson.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第十
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Congratulations on winning the Teacher of the Year Award.
Thank you, Peter.
I'm more than happy to be here.
What inspired you to be a teacher, Miss Johnson?
Well, I've always loved to learn, but I've enjoyed teaching others even more.
It's in the family.
Could you tell us what the best part about your job is?
Getting to know all of the different kids and communicating with them.
I have always loved kids, so I will always enjoy that part of my job.
Then what do you hope to achieve by being a teacher?
My goal is to help my students develop awareness of their strengths, weaknesses, and
learning needs, and to enable them to learn throughout their lives.
That sounds great.
Welcome to our program, Miss Johnson.
Congratulations on winning the Teacher of the Year Award.
Thank you, Peter.
I'm more than happy to be here.
What inspired you to be a teacher, Miss Johnson?
Well, I've always loved to learn, but I've enjoyed teaching others even more.
It's in the family.
Could you tell us what the best part about your job is?
Getting to know all of the different kids and communicating with them.
I have always loved kids, so I will always enjoy that part of my job.
Then what do you hope to achieve by being a teacher?
My goal is to help my students develop awareness of their strengths, weaknesses, and
learning needs, and to enable them to learn throughout their lives.
That sounds great.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Ethan, have you thought about getting your own house?
Yeah, but I'm convinced my parents love having me back.
What about you?
Um, not sure yet.
Right now, I enjoy getting my meals cooked for me every day.
Do you pay a contribution to the house?
course I do, but it's still much less than I would pay to live in my own flat,
right? Obviously. The only thing I don't like is that my mum wants to know every
part of my life.
Becky, what are you doing tomorrow?
Where? With whom?
The same questions every day.
Mums are like that.
They ask because they care.
You've got to be patient with them.
My parents ask those questions too, but I may not move out soon.
The thought of leaving them fills me with fear.
What if one of them falls over?
What if they both have a fall together?
That would be terrible.
What about you?
I'm not sure yet.
Right now, I enjoy getting my meals cooked for me every day.
What you pay a contribution to the house?
Of course I do, but it's still much less than I would pay to live in my own flat,
right? Obviously. The only thing I don't like is that my mum wants to know every
part of my life.
Becky, what are you doing tomorrow?
Where? With whom?
The same questions every day.
Mums are like that.
They ask because they care.
You've got to be patient with them.
My parents ask those questions too, but I may not move out soon.
The thought of leaving them fills me with fear.
What if one of them falls over?
What if they both have a fall together?
That would be terrible.
What sure yet.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十七
四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
my cooked day.
What I'm Right It's a pretty good conference, huh?
Yeah. All speakers are well known and knowledgeable in the subject matter.
Did you listen to John Miller's speech on how to avoid business risks this morning?
No, I missed that one.
I went to a speech at Allen Brown Hall.
The speaker was David Thompson.
Oh, that should be a good one too.
I attended his lecture last year.
By the way, there will be a workshop this afternoon on how to motivate employees.
Are you interested?
Sure. I was promoted to the position of manager a few months ago, and I have to
manage a staff of twelve people.
It can be quite a difficult situation sometimes.
That's why I am here today.
Same here. I only have seven people reporting to me, yet sometimes I feel like
pulling my hair out.
I need to find a way to create harmony within my department.
It's a pretty good conference, huh?
Yeah. All speakers are well known and knowledgeable in the subject matter.
Did you listen to John Miller's speech on how to avoid business risks this morning?
No, I missed that one.
I went to a speech at Allen Brown Hall.
The speaker was David Thompson.
Oh, that should be a good one too.
I attended his lecture last year.
By the way, there will be a workshop this afternoon on how to motivate employees.
Are you interested?
Sure. I was promoted to the position of manager a few months ago, and I have to
manage a staff of twelve people.
It can be quite a difficult situation sometimes.
That's why I am here today.
Same here. I only have seven people reporting to me, yet sometimes I feel like
pulling my hair out.
I need to find a way to create harmony within my department.
Listen questions. Welcome to Star Fitness Club.
听下面一段独白，回答第十八至第二十三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟。
的时间阅读这三个小题
I'm Tina Harrison.
Before you start, I'd like to offer you some tips.
We all know that regular exercise is important, but few of us know how to exercise
properly. I've seen many people make the same workout mistakes in this place.
One mistake people often make is sticking to the same routine.
It is not good for building up your muscles.
I'd like to suggest that you change your routine every other month.
What's more, you can try different kinds of such as jogging, biking, or swimming.
This can help keep your whole body in shape.
Another mistake most people make is to workout intensely almost every day.
You need to give your body a break and allow time for the muscles to grow.
It is not the harder the better.
Two hard workout days every week is enough.
If you really hate to skip a you can plan easy exercises on other days.
However, experts' suggestion is that you take one day off completely each week.
Welcome to Star Fitness Club.
I'm Tina Harrison.
Before you start, I'd like to offer you some tips.
We all know that regular exercise is important, but few of us know how to exercise
properly. I've seen many people make the same workout mistakes in this place.
One mistake people often make is sticking to the same routine.
It is not good for building up your muscles.
I'd like to suggest that you change your routine every other month.
What's more, you can try different kinds of such as jogging, biking, or swimming.
This can help keep your whole body in shape.
Another mistake most people make is to workout intensely almost every day.
You need to give your body a break and allow time for the muscles to grow.
It is not the harder the better.
Two hard workout days every week is enough.
If you really hate to skip a you can plan easy exercises on other days.
However, experts' suggestion is that you take one day off completely each week.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
on Thank you for watching.
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you for watching.
听力部分第一次考试到此结束。